三名触能者对大众宣战
Three of the Touched declared war on society.
目前你们每人都成了嫌疑者
Right now, every one of you is suspect.
蒙迪督察  似乎
AMALIA TRUE: Inspector Mundi clearly has
与玛丽有些私人利害关系
a personal interest in Mary Brighton.
玛丽的异能是什么
What is Mary's turn?
让玛丽开口唱
PENANCE ADAIR: You get Mary singin',
召唤所有触能者
all the Touched, they'll all come to us.
你打算正式经营菲礼曼俱乐部
You're turning your club into a business.
梅森认为触能者是瘟疫
Massen thinks the Touched are a plague.
我认为是宝藏
I think they're a gold mine.
我俩可以合伙
We can be partners.
你是其中一人吗
Are you one of them?
我一直想找出那个火花
I keep looking for that spark.
也许黑暗就在她计划之中
Maybe your darkness is part of her plan.
我要在她杀死玛丽之前找到麦拉蒂
AMALIA: I'm going to find Maladie before Mary's dead.
辛苦你了  折腾一整天
I'm sorry for your terrible day.
大家来吧
Come on, lads.
好极了
Pretty.
去告诉乞丐王  别想在这一带码头混了
Tell the Beggar King he's done on these docks.
不付钱就别想运货
No pay-ups. No shipments.
从这里到迪克码头
From here straight to Dicker's Wharf,
莱姆豪斯区归火焰安妮管
Limehouse belongs to Bonfire Annie.
我们走
Thug: Let's go.
看他要亲自或派人来跟我谈
He decides to argue the case, or send anyone else to,
就不信他找得到靠山
there's not a shadow he can hide in.
我这座靠山如何
Amalia: Not even this one?
这招如何
-Amalia: How about that one?
说说看我为何不该杀你
Tell me why I shouldn't kill you. -
你早该杀了我
I think you should, uh-- -
- 去你的  - 我灭火筒里装的量  足以把你包成木乃伊
Fuck off. -I've enough snuffer in here to mummify you.
- 你也一样  楚夫人  - 什么
The same goes for you, Mrs. True. -What?
情况比原先说的还要暴力
This scenario's a slight more violent than advertised.
- 你说要找她谈话  - 我们是啊  这就是我们的语言
You said we were going to speak. -We are. This is our language.
- 那你没比她好到哪里去  - 我比她好多了
And now you're no better than her. -I am much better than her.
- 动手打人就是不对  - 吵死了
Not if you punch her in the face-- -Christ!
别再喷了
Don't. All right.
好  来谈和吧
Parlay.
想说什么快说  再听到你俩吵架
You can speak your peace, but I will burn us all to death
我就放火同归于尽
if I have to hear you bicker.
潘妮丝  你先去灭火  以免火势扩大
Penance, you think maybe you could put out that fire before it spreads?
我们不会打架
Uh... -We won't fight.
她怎么有办法偷袭我
How in fuck's name did that girl sneak up on me?
我们比你还早到
Amalia: We were here before you were.
乞丐王的手下不怎么细心
The Beggar King's men aren't notably attentive.
潘妮丝甚至打了个喷嚏
Penance even sneezed once.
- 你怎么知道我在这里  - 我看见了
How'd you know I was here? -I saw it.
我看见火焰和马车  我的转变能力就是能预视
The fire, the cart. It's my "turn." Ripplings.
我还是有点想杀了你
I do still want to kill you a bit.
尽管动手  被她发现我可不帮你说话
Go ahead. But I'm not covering for you when she finds out.
我不知道麦拉蒂的下落
I don't know where Maladie is,
我也不打算自首
and I'm not turning myself in,
我希望你加入我们
or any kind of-- -I want you to join us.
到孤儿院来
At The Orphanage. -
- 你刚才说想杀我  - 人就是矛盾
And you want to kill me. -We're all contradictions.
你差点杀了我的挚友
You nearly killed my best friend,
却也救了我
and you saved my life.
- 那是不小心的  - 那是你的反射动作
Yeah, that was an accident. -It was a reflex.
我认为是你的本能
I think it was your natural instinct.
我的本能是放火烧东西
My natural instinct is to burn things down.
这点我们承受得住
We can accommodate that.
这就是你的使命吗
Is that the mission you were going on about?
玛丽布莱顿唱催眠曲  召唤所有触能者
Mary Brighton brings in all the Touched with her little lullaby,
- 然后推翻君政  - 没那么冠冕堂皇
then we overthrow the monarchy. -Nothing that grand.
也没那么小家子气
Or that small.
我离开麦拉蒂了  受不了她老是打哑谜
I quit Maladie 'cause I was sick of riddles.
反正也没继续赚钱
And we'd stopped making money.
许多人丧生了  我们触能者
You know we're dying. The Touched.
我们遭到攻击  囚禁  丢到大街上
We're being attacked, locked up, and thrown in the street.
不是每个触能者的转变  都能吓阻人
Not everyone got such a formidable "turn."
情况愈来愈糟  你也有未知的敌人
And it's getting worse. You have enemies you don't know about yet.
所以要我躲在  你们那帮可怜蠢蛋背后吗
So I should hide with your sad little gaggle?
我靠自己就行
I'm fine all by myself.
你的感受还在
You still feel it.
玛丽那天唱的歌  你知道有更美好的世界
Mary's song. You know what a better world could be like.
那份感受不是真的
It isn't real, that feeling.
只是幻想而已  你跟我一样不相信
It's a fantasy. You don't trust it any more than I do.
干脆去吸那整车  被我烧毁的鸦片
Might as well have been that cart full of opium I just torched.
整车的什么
Cart full of what? -
别滚嘛  宝贝
Penance: Don't roll away, lovely.
我会补偿你的
I'll make it up to you.
我跌在我的灭火筒上
I fell on my snuffer.
我不喜欢那些迎面而来的烟
I don't like all that smoke to come at me.
这位英雄垫住我才没受伤
This hero broke my fall.
我的背没事
My back feels fine.
感觉刺刺的  跟我的手指一样
Tingling, like my hand fingers.
她发现了更美好的世界
She found a better world. -
好多个我
Ugh. That's too many of me.
艾梅莉亚  来看我的灵魂  困在罐子里
Amalia, come and see my soul trapped in a jar.
轻轻摩擦  我能许你愿望
If you rub it, I'll give you wishes.
你绝对猜不到那火是什么
You'll never guess what the fire was.
- 是鸦片  亲爱的  - 是空气
It's opium, my love. -But it was the air.
也是渴望雷电的云
But also the cloud that wanted thunder
却因为太轻柔而留不住它
but was too gentle to hold it.
火焰安妮走掉了
Ugh... Bonnie Annie's gone away.
好了  今晚吸够多鸦片了
Come on. That's enough opium for tonight.
不然还是
Well, maybe just...
我去看看  你在这里等
Okay, let me check. You stay here.
你感受到那不是雷的雷吗
Did you feel the thunder that wasn't?
我常有这种感觉
I feel it all the time.
我们的工作最棒了
We have the best jobs.
火焰安妮断然拒绝
Amalia: Bonfire Annie, a flat no.
玛丽惊吓过度唱不出来
Mary's too shaken to sing.
茉朵的转变没人听得懂
Myrtle's "turn" is being incomprehensible.
我可真是成功在望
I am really racking up the wins.
- 还有  麦拉蒂是我一手造成的  - 你明知不是这样
Oh, and I created Maladie. -You know you didn't.
- 你做了困难的抉择  - 问题是她又不知道
You made a difficult choice. -She doesn't know that.
我都快忘记她了  这样似乎更糟糕
I still hardly remember her. Makes it worse, somehow.
请深呼吸  别说话
Breathe without talking, please.
可以了
All right.
你的冒险之夜对肺没好处
Your lungs are no better for your wild night out.
所幸伤口没破裂
You managed not to rupture a wound.
潘妮丝呢  她止住呕吐了
And Penance? She did stop vomiting.
她很坚强
She's a strong girl.
但是你不该带她
But you got no business bringing her along
去冒险
on these dangerous excursions,
毕竟麦拉蒂对她做过那种事
after what Maladie did to her.
我又没带她去找麦拉蒂
I didn't bring her to Maladie's.
你不晓得会遇上什么状况
You didn't know what you were walking into.
两次都是  你一直都这样
Either time. Any time.
设法把安妮带进孤儿院
Right, you tried to bring Bonfire Annie into the fold.
不是困难抉择  而是鲁莽轻率
That's not a difficult choice. That's just reckless.
- 她可是杀人凶手  - 我也是杀人凶手
She's a killer, for Christ's sake. -I'm a killer.
你是士兵  但潘妮丝不是
You're a soldier, and Penance isn't one.
- 她会是的  - 是朋友就不该愿她遭逢此厄运
She will be. -That's a terrible fate to wish on a friend.
发生的事有哪件如我所愿的
Do you think anything that's happening has to do with what I wish?
请别让她变成鸦片烟鬼
Just try to keep her from becoming an opium fiend.
你也知道年轻人不听老人言
Well, you know young people these days. They never listen.
对  你也不是好榜样
Yeah, and they're not gonna learn it from you.
- 何瑞休  - 这并不好笑
Horatio. -It's not funny.
一点也不有趣
It's not fun.
眼睁睁看你
Watching you throw yourself at danger
恣意投身险境
like you think it's gonna propose.
一再到这里
Coming here,
- 来为你疗伤  - 可以很有趣的
to patch you up over and over-- -It could be fun.
- 艾梅莉亚  我们已经说过了  - 当时很有趣
Amalia, we've been through this. -It was fun.
不只有趣而已
It was more than fun.
我每天晚上
Every night I have... -
看谁跑得快
Race you! -
我和妻子一起吃晚餐
I sit at dinner across from my wife,
我知道一些她不知道的事
and I know something that she doesn't know.
会让她痛彻心扉的事
Something that will pull her heart out,
唯一让我稍感宽慰的
and the only comfort I have or I could give
就是知道我已经抽身
is the knowledge that I walked away from it.
你并没断得一干二净
You didn't get very far.
难道对我而言很轻松吗
Do you think it's easy for me?
艾梅莉亚·楚的事都不轻松
Horatio: Nothing's easy for Amalia True.
她肩负拯救世界之重责
She has the weight of the world.
抱歉我无法大方承认  我是你的错误
I'm sorry I can't be more generous about being your mistake.
凯西和金红发女孩跳华尔滋
Casey would waltz with a strawberry blonde ?
乐声悠扬演奏
All: ? And the band played on ?
他和心仪女孩一同翩翩滑步
He'd glide 'cross the floor with a girl he adored ?
乐声悠扬演奏
And the band played on ?
但他脑中千头万绪
But his brain was so loaded ?
可怜的女孩吓得发抖
Poor girl would shake with delight ?
他和金红发女孩永不分离
All: ? He'd ne'er leave the girl with the strawberry curls ?
乐声悠扬演奏
? And the band played on... ? -
不必因为我停下来  请继续
No need to stop on my account, please.
你有想听的歌曲吗  楚夫人
Is there a song you'd like, Mrs. True?
都是你们没听过的  请继续唱
None you'd know, but keep playing.
楚夫人要的是另一种歌曲
-Mrs. True needs a different kind of song.
我得努力找回那天的声音
I should be working to get that voice back.
就让她弹琴吧
Oh, let her play.
可以别把我当成坏人吗
Can I not be made the villain of the piece?
我都说了请继续唱
I said keep playing.
时候到了那首歌就会出现
The other song will come when it comes.
开心一点只有好处  没坏处
I doubt a little fun will do anything but help.
等待期间没事做才会痛苦
Waiting's only painful when you're not doing anything else.
艾梅莉亚·楚在传福音了  她是耐心的守护神
The gospel of Amalia True, patron saint of patience,
同时也是揍人的守护神  大家早
and ironically, fist-punching. Good morning.
艾戴尔小姐 今早居然如此精力充沛
Miss Adair, you're surprisingly sprightly this morning.
我昨晚边呕吐时突发奇想
I had a vision in the night in between vomits.
上次玛丽在众人面前唱
First time Mary sang in public,
只有剧院里的触能者听到
only the Touched that were in the room could hear it.
下次我打算让玛丽的歌声
But next time, we'll make Mary's voice loud enough
让全城触能者都听见
that it can be heard by Touched across the city--
你是指坎多马斯公园吧
You say Candlemas Park is the place, right?
那里很空旷  而且
It's open on all sides, and there's the--
而且位于市中心
Penance: And it's right in the center of the city.
但昨晚我也注意到城市很吵杂
But I was noticing last night that the city is loud.
就算真言也难敌噪音
Even pure truth would choke on the din.
说穿了声音就是振动波
But every voice is just vibrations,
可以用电能转换器将音波
and an electric converter could make those vibrations
放大
a lot bigger.
潘妮丝艾戴尔  你发明了扩音器吗
Penance Adair, have you just invented the amplifier?
你破坏惊喜了
Ah, you gave it away!
而且还取了无聊的名字
And you gave it a very dull name.
我称之为布莱扬声器
I'll be calling it "The Brightener."
改编自你的姓氏
It's a play on words involving your name.
谢谢你
Well, thanks.
我不懂它的作用
Um, that's... Um, I-I don't know what it is.
它可以
Oh, it, um..
扩大音波
amplifies the sound waves.
让你的声音传到几哩外
It-it'll make your voice heard for miles,
或将近一哩
or near a mile, I think.
看起来四四方方的  设计部分晚点再想
They're-they're awful boxy. Design elements usually come later on.
只需一些铜线
But all I need is some copper wire,
我就能做出原型
and we'll have some prototypes.
不如晚点我们到公园去
I say we go to the park
先做些测试
later on this evening, and we just run some tests.
我还以为我睡饱了
And to think I slept.
你向来不够看
You always were a lightweight.
我想我快要能唱了
Look, I think I am getting closer to it.
我有些微的感觉
I mean, I-- I feel little moments.
不必每次见到我就向我报告
You don't have to give me a status report every time you see me.
虽然你目前已能谈笑风生
Just because you can enjoy yourself and be entertaining
但你一周前才刚遭人绑架
doesn't mean you weren't kidnapped a week ago.
顺其自然吧
It'll come when it comes.
有麦拉蒂的消息吗
Has there been any word of Maladie?
她大概在疗伤中
I imagine she's licking her wounds.
或痛揍伤口
Or punching them.
火焰安妮呢
And Bonfire Annie?
听说你昨晚找她加入我们
Heard you were trying to recruit her last night.
- 你好啊  - 你不高兴
Hello, miss. -Amalia: Does that bother you?
- 走开  - 我希望你能先告诉我
Get out. -Mary: I wish I'd been told.
万一我突然看见她
If I turned a corner and there she was--
我不想无端烦扰你
I didn't want to worry you for nothing.
反正这事也没下文
And nothing is what came of it, so...
你有秘密
You're keeping secrets.
每个女人都有秘密
Every woman keeps secrets.
触能者的秘密又更多了
Every Touched woman keeps a great deal more.
你没正面回答
That's a dodge.
你有什么疑问吗
Was there a question?
我问孤儿院的人  这是什么样的地方
I've asked the girls what this place is,
为何聚集在这里
and what we're meant to be doing.
每个人都有不同答案
And they all have different answers.
我能感觉到有些什么
I can sense that there's something--
除了互相保护外另有使命
Some sort of mission beyond keeping each other safe.
但有些模糊不清
But it's all a bit vague.
你想找出什么
What is it you're looking for?
阴谋还是邪教
A conspiracy? A cult?
- 我又没要你割断脚趾  - 我想找的是你
I'm not asking you to cut off your toes. -I'm looking for you.
- 我就在这里  - 是吗
I'm right here. -Are you?
三年前 我突然知道了  不该知道的事
Three years ago, I woke up knowing things that I shouldn't,
旁人说我疯了
and was declared insane.
我也曾经以为我疯了
Which for a time, I thought I was.
所以没错  我有秘密没说
So, yes, I keep secrets.
我也酗酒  故意跟人打架
I also drink when I shouldn't, fight when I needn't,
包括跟不认识的男人
and fuck men whose names I do not learn.
我在人群中容易紧张
I get nervous in crowds.
我看见不存在的事物
I see things that aren't there.
每次初识人  就想着如何杀死对方
When I meet someone, the first thing I think of is how to kill them.
我也有一些优点
I do have some good qualities.
我真心喜欢马
I genuinely like horses.
你本来不该知道的事是什么
What is it you know that you shouldn't?
你要我唱歌召唤更多触能者
You want me to sing so that more people will come here?
也许我唱不出  是因为不确定他们该来
Maybe I'm struggling because I don't know if they should.
就是现在
Hugo: Yes! Now!
快点展现
Tell me!
９点４２分１１秒
Nine, forty-two and eleven seconds!
紫色的光芒呢
Wh-where's the purple light?
你在说什么
You're supposed to fill the room with light
你高潮时应该照亮整个房间
when you spend.
我没办法照亮
I don't fill the room--
我要的是紫色光  不是格林威治平均时间
I wanted purple light! Not Greenwich Mean Time.
我知道正确时间
Uh, I know the time.
没人要雇用触能者了
-No one hires the Touched no more.
雨果  抱歉突然闯进来
Hugo, sorry to barge in.
我想我们
I just, I think-- I think we're being very, um...
奥古  见过多敏妮  她来应征的
Augie, this is Dominique. She's been auditioning.
原来如此
Oh. I see. No, I see, I see.
祝你好运
Best of luck.
你亲自面试所有女性吗
: Do you-- Do you audition all the girls?
还有男性。有一对龙凤胎兄妹
Uh, and the boys. I've got a set of, uh, boy-girl twins
两人间的连结很神奇
who are bonded in the most fascinating way.
- 打一人屁股  另一人会  - 雨果
If you spank one of them, the other-- -Oh, Hugo...
我不确定想参与你的生意
I'm just not sure I can be involved with this.
合约已经签好了  老友
It's all signed and sealed, old boy.
你还没寄给公司
But you haven't filed them yet
注册处吧
with the-- with the company's house.
- 你一签好就寄出去了  - 当时是凌晨四点啊
Well, the moment they were signed. -What, 4:00 AM?
当天寄出去的  你是菲礼曼俱乐部唯一业主
The day they were signed. You are the sole proprietor of the Ferryman's Club,
而且还获利不少
and turning a pretty profit to boot.
- 他是老板  - 一点都没错
He's boss. -He is boss.
获利  这么快吗
Profit? Already?
合伙前我已付清一切开销
I paid this all off privately before we started.
就是服务人员  招待者
There's just, uh, the staff, the talent, and, uh,
以及我们丰厚的薪水
our generous salaries.
- 薪水  - 我知道  很俗气吧
Salaries? -I know. Isn't it common?
我们身旁尽是暴发户
We dwell amongst the nouveau riche.
我跟你面试吧
I audition to you?
雨果
Hugo. Hugo! Hugo...
- 万一拉薇娜知道了  - 她不会知道
If Lavinia finds out... -She won't.
你没投资半毛钱
You haven't invested a penny.
而且合约保密
And the contracts are under seal.
别笑  你得保持神秘
Uh, uh, don't smile. You have mystique.
触能者是拉薇娜个人志业
The Touched are her personal cause.
- 一旦发现你  - 下位应征者到了
Lavinia, if she finds out what you... -Your next candidate.
- 我们  是你叫他们做这些事  - 付钱请他们做
We... No, you are making them do-- -Paying them to do.
- 会付我钱  - 问他住所的事
Paying me to do. -Voice : Ask him... ask him for housing...
提供住所给他们  你别吵
And housing them. Quiet, you.
- 让他们安身立命  - 雨果  此事非同小可
And keeping them safe. -Hugo, this isn't a schoolyard prank.
这里有些行为并不合法
There are things being done here that are illegal.
而且可能不道德
And quite, quite possibly immoral.
说到这个  夏绿蒂向你问好
Speaking of which, uh, Charlotte says hello.
- 还有露菲玛  - 雨果
Uh, so does Lufima. -Hugo.
- 你该不会  - 帮我拿着
You wouldn't... -There you are.
我那晚的举止
Augie: Wh-wha-what I did that night
确实不合宜
was not the conduct of a gentleman, I know.
但并没有违法
But w-- We didn't-- We didn't break any laws.
- 据我所知没有  - 法律还管不到你那天干的事
That I know of. -What you did, they don't have laws for.
那我就没违法了
Then I didn't break any.
试试看再说
Look, just give it a try.
我孤身一人
I'm all alone here, Augie.
无法包办所有事情
I-I can't do all this all by myself.
我没时间
I don't have the time.
- ９点４０  - 闭嘴
Nine forty-- -No!
一切发生得太快
Everything's just moving much too fast.
抱歉那么快寄出申请
I'm, I'm sorry I filed the papers,
我得用上很多人情  我没办法
but I had to use up a lot of favors, and I can't help--
当然有朝一日会放你走  给我一点时间
I-- Of course, I will. I'll-I'll set you free. Just give me time.
同时不如享受一下当老板
And, and meanwhile, enjoy being in charge for a bit,
- 我得去开个会  - 让我当老板吗
'cause I have a meeting. -No-- In charge?
你不需要面试任何人
Well, you don't have to audition anyone. Just...
摆个架子就好  一直说＂不行＂  若玛
look important. Say no a lot. Roma!
不是说她会发出紫光吗
Where the hell is my purple light?
干吗送个怀表来
You sent me a pocket watch.
现在立刻把合约送去
: And can you get those fucking contracts filed now?
不行吗
No?
小心
Below!
罗纳会在您回来前
Mrs. Beechum: Ronald will have those maple branches pruned
修剪好枫树树枝
before you get back.
这工会的事应该几天就能解决
This union business should only take a few days.
工会不过是懒人组织
Unions is just organized laziness,
请见谅我这么说
if you don't mind my saying.
有薪水领和您英明领导  就该感激了
Should be grateful for a wage and your guiding hand.
这一团乱是怎么回事
What the hell is all this?
不过装个电话线  又不是高空秋千
We're installing a telephone, not a trapeze.
我会让人清理干净的
I'll make sure they're out of sight.
进步所带来的危害
The degradation of progress.
建立家园是为了阻挡外侮
We build homes to keep other people out,
却又造了机器引进外籍劳工
and then build machines to let them all in.
去肉铺买东西确实会方便很多
Well, it will help with ordering from the butchers and such.
- 加快速度  - 反正现在只用速度
Speed it up. -Yes, because the measure of a thing's worth
来衡量价值
is how quickly it arrives.
若您临时决定回来  或携伴回来
Well, if you was to come unexpectedly, or with company...
管家助手听见  您和帕金斯
It's only the under-butler heard you talking to Parkins
谈及一位寡妇
about a widow you'd met.
彼洛夫人的朋友
A friend of Miss Bidlow's.
你会开除他吧
You'll fire him yourself?
知道了  老爷
Of course, sir.
毕钦太太
And Mrs. Beechum, you will give up
别再妄想我续絃
your romantic yen for a mistress.
目前家中人丁已是我容忍极限
This house has all the company I can abide.
安妮·卡尔毕
Little Annie Carbey,
莱姆豪斯区的一把火
the Bonfire of Limehouse.
从她还是小毛头我就认识了
I've known her since she was a dusky urchin,
跟着她父亲去
following her old man around
帮高帽党收保护费
when he collected for the Top Hat Lads.
现在她还有了转变能力
Now, she's got a "turn."
可怕的转变能力
A terrible fuckin' "turn."
火焰  你们拿什么跟她比
Fire. And what have you got that can compete with that?
你们不是有枪吗
You got fucking guns!
大家都看见你们逃跑
People saw you running.
任凭我的货被烧光
By the light of my shipment ablaze,
所有人都看见我乞丐王的手下
people saw the Beggar King's men on the run
打不过一个女孩子
from a fucking girl!
欧丁先生
Now, Mr. Odium here
想带你们去泰晤士河走走
wanted to take you for a walk along the Thames,
他知道替我办事的人
'cause he knows that when you wear my brand,
就代表我的形象
what you do reflects on me.
我又绕回去  但她已经走了
I circled back, but she'd gone.
另外两个女子也是
And the other ladies were there.
- 哪两个女子  - 寡妇
Other ladies? -The widow.
跟会发明的那个
And the science one.
她的装备很吓人
She had a horrible device.
我不知道她们
Well, I-I didn't know if they were gonna...
我会改进的
I'll do better. -Shh, shh, shh,
你的烙印还很新
Oh, no. How new that scar is.
你只是个新人
No, no. You're a pup!
反观
Ha! Now,
另一个跟了我八年的人
a man carrying my mark for eight years,
还以为他会坚守阵脚
I'd expect him to stand his ground.
也许已经厌倦替我办事
Maybe he's become tired of wearing my mark. Huh?
也许我的名号已成了负担
Maybe it's become a burden, my brand.
没人告诉我们会遇上什么
We wasn't told what to expect. -Oh.
痛苦和耻辱
Pain and disgrace.
没关系
But it's all right.
反正你就要遇上了
'Cause you're expecting it. -
楚夫人又在打什么鬼主意
So, what the fuck is Mrs. True up to now?
知道这是什么吗
You know about this?
有没有人看到是谁放我桌上的
Anyone see who left this?
小心
Below!
试试看阁楼
Mrs. Beechum: Try the attic,
注意东西别太碍眼
and make sure they're out of sight!
试试看阁楼
Humph. "Try the attic."
别指挥我做事行吗
Try not telling me my business, how about?
别靠近那些狗
Don't go near the dogs. -
它们有狂犬病  改走这里
They've gone rabid. Try around here.
听到那人说的吗
Can you believe that man?
＂女孩子不要乱玩电器＂
"Electronics is nothing for a girl to be dabbling in."
你何时看过我乱玩了  茉朵
Have you ever seen me dabble, Myrtle?
看我玩坏他的脸
I'll dabble his face.
楚夫人
Se?ora  True?
上面写了什么
What does it say?
这不是孤儿院的地址
Penance: That's not our address.
你偏好哪一种
Barmaid: What's your preference?
这里只卖两种啤酒
We only got two on tap.
来杯黑啤酒
A pint of the dark.
你们好
-Ladies.
- 柯森医生  见到你真好  - 抱歉  我认识你吗
Dr. Cousens. What a treat. -I'm sorry. Have we met?
当然认识
Oh, yes. As it happens, I promised you
其实我答应过送你一辆马车
your own carriage.
车子终于来了
And at last, it's here.
想不到你是说真的
Huh. I never thought you meant it.
我从不骗人  也未曾吹嘘
Ah, I never lie. I never boast.
其实一位富有的病患  正在车里等你
As it happens, a wealthy patient is waiting for you within.
你一点儿也不怕这位新病患
A new client, of whom you're not remotely afraid.
闭嘴  上校  别消除他的恐惧
Hush, Colonel. Don't take away his fear.
他可能会需要
He might need it.
你怕我吗
Are you afraid?
你报答医生的方式人尽皆知
It's well known how you pay your doctors.
我好好地答谢过他们的服务了
They were compensated in kind for the services they provided.
别对我脑子动手脚就没事
You don't mess about with brains, you're all right.
你知道我为哪些人服务
You know who I work with?
人尽皆知乞丐王
Everyone knows the Beggar King
有个妙手回春的医生
has a doctor on call with healing hands.
我知道  还有楚夫人
Yes, I know. Mrs. True.
但这跟她无关  而是她留给我的礼物
But this ain't about her. It's about the gift she gave me.
万一治好你  怎知你不会
And if I heal you, how do I know you won't--
杀了你  就为了向莫莉报仇
What, strike you down to get at Molly?
你这么担心
If you're frettin' on that,
想必你俩交情匪浅
you two must be... dear friends.
或是老交情了
Oh, you do go back a ways.
我们都一样
We all do.
只是我不太记得你
Except I don't remember you so well.
是有个穿医生袍的黑人
Although there was a Black in a doctor's coat,
还以为是我的幻想
which I thought my mind made up.
不是
No...
我确实存在
I'm real.
让我看看你的伤口
Do you want to show me the wound?
当然好  遵命  医生
Yes, sir, doctor, sir.
是个顽强的小伤口
It's a persistent little pinhole.
用吻让它好起来
Kiss it better.
子弹碎片还在里面
Hmm. Still a bullet fragment in there.
得先取出才能治疗伤口
I'll have to take it out before I can help you.
会很痛的
This is going to hurt.
拜托一定要痛
Promise?
那人留下这个
Man gave me this.
他叫我等两小时再给你  抱歉
I was told to wait two hours. Sorry.
再来一杯威士忌
And another whiskey.
史旺
Frank: Swann.
- 长得还不错  - 还行
Not bad on the eyes. -Yeah, all right, though.
希望我们没惹上麻烦
Hope we aren't in trouble.
我有时觉得你故意露出马脚
Sometimes I think you want to get caught.
- 女酒保说你在这里  - 是吗
Barmaid told me you were here. -Did she?
不可能
Mmm, no, no.
她跟我是好知己  我从今天中午就认识她了
She and I are bosom friends. I've known her since half noon.
她不会出卖我
She wouldn't squidge on me.
总有一天你会落入
One day, you're gonna walk into a place
一个你吃不开的地方
that don't think you're charming.
而且不稀罕你的臭钱
Don't think your money's charming.
- 我的钱可香了  - 你究竟在干吗  史旺
My money is adorable. -What are you doing, Swann?
你整天都在忙什么
What are you spending your day doing
自以为是大反派莫里亚蒂  玩些狗屁诡计
with this panto Moriarty crap?
你以为工作是这么一回事吗
This what you think a job feels like?
我工作可认真了  督察
I'm-- I'm worked to the bone, Inspector.
倒是你没给我半点  楚夫人和孤儿院的
Whilst I've had nothing of worth from you about Amalia True,
有用消息
or The Orphanage.
知道安排那次搜索要多少钱吗
Do you know what it cost to arrange that raid?
你希望我找到什么
What do you think I'll find, hmm?
一堆女孩向往离开安全的社群
A bunch of girls longing to leave the safety of their community
- 到你店里卖淫吗  - 有几个也不错
to come whoring for you? -Uh, a few.
你有这方面的天份
You do have a talent for it.
玛丽·布莱顿呢
What about Mary Brighton?
我是问她的转变
Her "turn," I mean.
我说过了  是一首歌
I told you. It's a song.
只有触能者听得见
Only the Touched can hear it.
会让他们快乐
It makes 'em feel happy.
艾梅莉亚楚为一首摇篮曲  冒生命危险
Amalia True risks life and limb for a lullaby.
- 不可能只有这样  - 玛丽完全不知道楚夫人的计划
No, there's more. -Mary don't know anything about Mrs. True's plans.
玛丽在婚礼当天抛弃你
Mary left you on your wedding day.
说她有事会瞒着你并不为过
I think it's safe to say she does keep things from you.
当然  她帮了你一把
She did you a favor, of course.
经历如此惨痛失望
Such a dramatic disappointment.
没人会质疑你不愿
No one would question you not rushing to the altar
再踏入婚姻
a second time. -
我常在想
I often wonder,
是她知道自己永远无法满足你
did she realize she could never give you what you wanted,
还是她发现我可以
or did she find out I was?
我当时醉了
I was drunk!
我当时喝得烂醉
I was blind drunk.
菲礼曼俱乐部客人络绎不绝
The Ferryman's is a massive venture.
超乎我所预期
More even than I'd hoped.
但非做出大规模改变不可
But it depends on an immeasurable level of change.
艾梅莉亚·楚
Amalia True?
我才不相信她只想
I do not believe she has any interest
给触能者安全庇护  你相信吗
in giving the Touched a safe haven. Do you?
不相信
No.
她说能预视未来  但并未全盘托出
Seeing the future... that ain't her whole story.
- 她别有目的  - 现在她把玛丽留在身边
She has a purpose. -And now she has Mary.
为什么
Why? -
看看你
Look at you.
躲在暗处还惧怕阴影
A shadow afraid of shadows.
真是孤单寂寞
Such a lonely life.
是吗
Yeah?
你的朋友又在哪里
Where are all your friends then?
是第一次  法兰克
The first time, Frank. -
只有第一次是因为你醉了
You were drunk the first time.
我脚趾好痒
My toes itch.
剩下的脚趾还是砍断的
The ones you've got, or the ones you haven't?
都痒
Both.
新月让我变成处女
The new moon has made me a virgin.
伤口表面还有点发炎
There's still some infection on the surface. -
拿去  一天吃两颗
Here. Take two of these a day,
伤口保持干净
and keep it clean.
这就赎了莫莉的罪过
Is this what Molly's atonement looked like?
这样就够了吗
You think it's enough?
我认为你为了她所不能控制的事而责怪她
I think you blame her for something she couldn't control.
不晓得到时你会责怪谁
I wonder who you'll blame when the time comes.
你走吧
On you go.
叫我走  这可是我的车
Go? This is my carri...
不许抓伤口
Don't scratch at it.
威尼马·克鲁  站起来
Winemar Kroos, get up.
- 怎么回事  - 闭上臭嘴快走
What's this? -Shut your cunt and come on.
放你出去时记得把锁射坏
Shoot up a new lock when they let you out.
你这幸运的王八羔子
You're the luckiest fuck in the world.
- 可以把武器还我吗  - 闭嘴
Can I please have my weapon? -Shut it!
我需要
I need it!
光天化日张贴在闹市里
Hanging in the market in broad daylight.
看来已经有段时日了
Been out there a while by the state of it.
不晓得还有多少张
I have no idea how many more there are.
我倒是没看过
Oh, I didn't know about these.
我经常外出
I mean, I'm out and about more than most.
照理说应该看过才对
I feel like I should have seen. -Penance: Mmm.
现在你看到了  我们亲自登门拜访
You can see now. Time for a visit.
我俩很久没一块儿出门玩了
Been long since you and I did a proper ladies' out, isn't it?
说得没错
It has, as that.
来了
Yes! Yes, I'm coming!
你们是谁
Who are you?
你们来这里干吗
What on Earth is this all about?
我的妈呀  他可真丑
Fuck a drumstick, he's ugly.
他是来抓茉朵的人之一吗
Is this one of those guys what come after Myrtle?
没错
Amalia: He was.
这是什么
Lucy: What is it?
你先把帅哥跟老太婆带回孤儿院
Get handsome to The Orphanage and take grandmother with you.
- 需要车资吗  - 不用  我有钱
You need fare? -No, no, no, no. I've got money.
不是偷来的
It's not from stealing.
得查出他们做了些什么
We need to know everything that they've been doing.
黛瑟蕾会让他们招来
Ah, Désirée will get it out of her.
不然就由我动手
Or I will.
潘妮丝还在测试那个玩意儿吗
Is Penance still doing her what's-it test?
对  得在玛丽开口唱前让一切就绪
Yes. We need to be set up the day Mary is ready to sing.
我傍晚直接去公园和潘妮丝会合
I'll meet Penance in the park at dusk.
你上哪儿去
Where are you going?
拿这些去给彼洛夫人看
Miss Bidlow needs to see this.
法兰克
Frank.
我
Hi. -I, uh...
我没有要你赶过来的意思
I, um, didn't mean for you to rush over.
不想浪费你的时间
I don't want to waste your time.
我有足够人手  没关系
Oh, no, I've got other people doing that, thanks.
- 你该不会  - 不是的
But you're not in any... -No, no, no.
不是什么大事
No. Noth-- nothing dire. Just, um...
我想麦拉蒂应该还没落网
Well, I... I, I don't suppose that Maladie's been, um,
被遣往澳洲吧
oh, you know, captured and sent off to Australia.
发生什么事了吗
Did, did something happen?
楚夫人有什么计划吗
Is-is Mrs. True up to something?
尽管告诉我  不会列入纪录的
I mean, you, you can tell me. It's unofficial, of course.
不是  只是情况比我预期的还要奇怪
No. It's just stranger than I expected,
跟一群触能者住在一起
you know, being around so many of the Touched. It's...
我的
My, my...
歌曾经只属于自己
my song used to be mine. It was like a little...
能抚慰我的心灵
little piece of comfort.
现在公诸于世了
But then, now that I've gone public, it just...
我不知道
I don't...
要如何
I don't know how to find that...
找回歌声
voice that I have. -Uh...
我可以帮你另找住处
I could-- I could-- I could find you a place.
再不然的话
You know I've got that, the spare room,
我家也有空房间
if there, there's nothing else.
- 我不会对你  - 我知道
And I, I wouldn't try to-- -No, it's...
我知道你不会
I know you wouldn't.
法兰克  我不是那个意思
I, I-- Frank, I didn't mean it-- it's, uh...
我知道你是绅士  所以不会逾矩
As, as a gentleman, I know that you wouldn't.
但以身为男人的角度也一样
But also as a man who...
法兰克
Frank...
你是好人
You're a good man.
但是你憎恨自己某个部分
But there's a part of you that you hate.
我不会多说
I, I won-- I won't say any more.
只想告诉你
Except that...
我永远不会恨你
I will never hate you.
不会因你的本性而恨你
Not for who you are.
你永远是我有麻烦时会找的人
You'll always be the man that I call when there's trouble,
没有麻烦时也一样
and when there's not trouble, I guess.
- 可以拜托你一件事吗  - 当然
Can I ask you for something? -Of course.
你下次唱歌时
N-next time you sing,
不是一般的那种
not that, that kind of singing...
我也想在场
I-I'd like to be there.
你知道只有触能者听得到吧
You know that only the Touched can hear it.
我只是想
Yeah, I want to feel like,
至少可以试试看
'cause at least just give it a go.
人都会改变
People change.
最糟也不过就是用看的
At the worst, I'll watch.
我很久没看你登台唱歌了
It's been a long while since I've seen you on a stage.
已经安排就绪了  我们
Arrangements have already been made, and we, uh--
- 抱歉没等你来就开始  - 无妨
Forgive us, we have to begin. -Of course, of course.
我从电话里已大概明白了
I got the gist on my telephone.
我们对投资报酬抱有多大信心
What are the confidence levels on the investment's return?
很遗憾地  我们无法预视未来
Regrettably, we are among those who cannot see into the future.
但我们对局势一清二楚
But we do have a clearer view of the field.
看来新加入者开始动作了
It appears the new players are in motion.
得把那些传单撕下来
We need to get those fliers taken down.
- 也许已传遍全伦敦  - 别拿下来
They could be all over London. -Leave them.
我会派人看着那栋房子  以防有人找上门
I'll have someone watch the house in case anyone turns up,
不论知情或不知情者
innocent or otherwise.
- 我可以做些什么  - 我要知道那栋房子主人是谁
What can I do? -I need to know who owns the building.
我这一两天就能查出
I can get that information for you in a day or so.
但我认为帮助不大
Although I doubt it will reveal much.
玛丽·布莱顿怎么样了
What about Mary Brighton?
她发得出  召唤声吗
Is she doing her siren call, or what have you?
我不确定  她一直力不从心
Amalia: I'm not sure. She's been struggling.
我们今晚会在公园测试
We're doing the test this evening, in the park.
若玛丽唱得出来  我们会让所有触能者听见
If Mary can find her voice, we'll make sure it's heard.
你跟她们说了什么
Distorted voice: What did you tell them?
什么
What...
What? What--
我什么都没说
N-nothing. I-I never said--
- 跟她们说了什么  - 我发誓
What did you tell them?! -I, I, I, s-swear.
什么也没说
I, I didn't tell anyone anything.
我没有
I didn't!
你已情绪高涨
Désirée: Well, now that your blood is up,
可以开始了
how's about we start then? -
你们是谁
Who are all you people?
我们是看传单找上你的人
We're the people who answer your flier.
我不会回答你们的问题
Well, I'm not answering any of your questions.
你替谁工作
Who do you work for?
一个男人  很高  穿毛皮大衣
A man. Tall. Had a fur coat.
说话得体但不至太高贵
Well-spoken but not too posh.
你以为老板本人会抛头露面吗
You think they'd send the boss around, showin' his face?
他们把那些女孩怎么了
What do they do to the girls?
我想是做实验吧
Experiments, I think.
- 为何选上你  - 大概知道了我不堪的过去
Why you? -They knowed about my tragedy, I guess.
关于我女儿受的折磨
About my daughter, and all the suffering.
你听见任何名字吗
Did you hear a name?
水  她能把所有东西变成水
Water. She made everything water.
任何液体都行  她把酒变成水
Any liquid. She did it with wine,
跟耶稣做的相反
which is the opposite of Jesus.
那酒可是花了我二先令
Plus, it cost me two shillings.
有一口井水让人喝了生病
There was a well, made everyone sick.
她处理好了
She fixed that,
但这不是一般人该做的事
but that's not for a person to do.
但她从不曾害怕
But she was never afraid of it.
她什么都不怕
She stopped being afraid of anything.
她总说  ＂水即生命＂
She would just say, "Water is life."
到了晚上她坐着做针线活
Sitting up nights with her needlework,
她知道一些事
just knowing something.
坐在那里  知道些什么
Sitting and knowing.
有个年轻人也看见了  那样不正常
A young man saw it, too. It was unnatural.
我心里祈求卸下她身上的重担
My heart bleeding for the burden
我身上的重担
on, uh, on, on me.
有天她去洗澡
And she went for a bath.
真的好难  好难
And it was so hard. It was so hard to...
把她压在水里  因为她不懂是怎么回事
hold her down like that 'cause she didn't understand.
她拍着水挣扎
She was splashing and struggling
想要叫救命
and trying to cry out.
我看得一清二楚  因为她把水变得清澈
I could see it all 'cause she made the water so clear.
我必须忍受
I had to bear that.
我必须坚强
I had to be strong...
直到她停止挣扎
till she stopped.
直到她终于自由
Till she was free.
她与肚子里的孩子
Her and the child inside her.
露西
-Lucy!
放开我
Let go of me!
露西
Lucy, Lucy, Lucy, Lucy, Lucy.
人神共愤  你们的存在人神共愤
Abominations! Abominations, all of you!
你们得
-You need to--
露西的转变来得很突然
Lucy's "turn" came sudden.
她不知道自己是触能者
She didn't know she was Touched
直到她从摇篮抱起儿子
till she lifted her baby boy up from his bassinet.
才六个月大  也是第一个  回应她的爱的人
Six months old and the first person to ever love her back.
他连哭都来不及就粉身碎骨
And all his bones broke before he could even make a sound.
她不会伤害你的
I don't think she would hurt ya.
我们得找警察来
We should call in the law.
她在七个人面前供认杀人
She confessed to murder in front of seven people.
我们是七个触能者  哪个警察会在乎
Yeah, seven Touched people. What policeman's gonna care?
蒙迪
Mundi.
布莱扬声器奏效  太好了
Your brightener worked a charm. That's good news.
还需要一些修改
Aye. It needs some tinkerin'.
但我现在没心情
But I'm not in much of a mind right now.
得通知楚夫人
We'll have to send word to True.
我们不去公园了
Tell her we're not going to the park.
我们得去
Mary: Yes, we are.
你说什么
Sorry?
我们得去公园  我准备好了
We are going to the park. I'm ready.
这机器能奏效吧
Will this be workin'?
可以的
Yes, ma'am.
请蒙迪督察过来
Tell Inspector Mundi to come.
通知大家到场  特别是露西
Let everyone know, especially Lucy.
共有几人
How many?
你说谁  哈丽叶
What, love?
触能者女孩
Girls...
再也听不见玛丽歌声的那些人
that'll never hear Mary's song.
刚才该问她多少人遇害
We should have asked her how many.
你就这么讨厌穿连衣裙吗
Is it that you just hate dresses?
有人惹到我了
Someone overstepped.
- 需要多少人做测试  - 这不是测试
How many people do you need for a test? -Oh, it's not a test.
我其实很喜欢的
I love them, you know.
- 喜欢谁  - 连衣裙
Who? -Dresses.
我觉得美极了
I think they're just wonderful.
不要啊
: No!
特效 折木
补充翻译  艾艾
补充翻译  冰林
补充翻译  Pretender
补充翻译  基因
合并校对：艾艾
翻译招募Q群：545053435
你不想做完
我当然想  刚才怎么回事
什么  你不满意吗
爱妻关朵琳之墓
爱女莉莉·梅森  卒于１８９６年
快到伯斯
德罗路
６号来
这就是浪费我时间的感觉